{"posts":[{"tags":[{"name":"forums"},{"name":"lab classes"},{"name":"week 02: big numbers"},{"name":"program","salience":0.30182358622550964},{"name":"addition","salience":0.24773070216178894},{"name":"time","salience":0.12101626396179199},{"name":"go","salience":0.08259016275405884},{"name":"revision","salience":0.08259016275405884},{"name":"operations","salience":0.046725183725357056},{"name":"task","salience":0.0447576530277729},{"name":"operations","salience":0.032039642333984375},{"name":"place value","salience":0.02817150391638279},{"name":"atoi","salience":0.012555121444165707}],"question":" Hi, I never managed to get this program working properly the first time around so I'm having another go at it for revision. Is it possible to complete this task using bitwise operations e.g. 0000000010 &amp; 0000000030 = 0000000060 I can complete it otherwise by using atoi() and performing formal addition on each place value but I feel like bitwise operations would be more effective if it can be implemented. ","answers":[]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums"},{"name":"lab classes"},{"name":"week 02: big numbers"},{"name":"binary files tests","salience":0.4695192277431488},{"name":"exp","salience":0.2128753662109375},{"name":"tests","salience":0.16817033290863037},{"name":"file","salience":0.14943507313728333}],"question":" Binary files tests/6.exp and tests/6.out differ How do I get and open the file? ","answers":[" Since tests/6.exp is not a binary file, then I assume that your program is producing a binary file. You can read what's in tests/6.exp simply by cat 'ing it. If you want to see what's in tests/6.out , try the command od -c tests/6.out This sounds like something to take to a Help Session , or ask your tutor in the lab. "]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums"},{"name":"lab classes"},{"name":"week 02: big numbers"},{"name":"quiz","salience":0.40019530057907104},{"name":"answer","salience":0.24077336490154266},{"name":"answers","salience":0.1356600970029831},{"name":"none","salience":0.11595886200666428},{"name":"code doesnt","salience":0.05980575457215309},{"name":"syntax errors","salience":0.04760660231113434}],"question":" quiz 2 q4 Isn't the answer to it \"none of these answers are correct\" since there are syntax errors and the code doesnt comply? ","answers":[" What syntax error did you get? ",[" wait nvm do we assume we run the code with header files and a main program? ",[" Yes you can assume that the code needs to be put inside a main function. "]]]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums"},{"name":"lab classes"},{"name":"week 02: big numbers"},{"name":"shepherd","salience":0.66817706823349},{"name":"raymond setiawan soedargo","salience":0.3181322515010834},{"name":"segmentation error","salience":0.013690706342458725}],"question":" Hi Dr. Shepherd! How are you? This is Raymond again! May I know what segmentation error means? Thank you. Raymond Setiawan Soedargo ","answers":[" It means you've dereferenced a pointer variable which contains a value which is not a valid address. E.g. int *p = 3; *p =42; will generate a segmentation error. Try also this explanation on Quora . ",[" Allright, thank you Dr. Shepherd! "]]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums"},{"name":"lab classes"},{"name":"week 02: big numbers"},{"name":"addbignums","salience":0.26885393261909485},{"name":"anyone","salience":0.17946693301200867},{"name":"pointer","salience":0.16825953125953674},{"name":"bignum n","salience":0.03816688433289528},{"name":"functions","salience":0.0317142978310585},{"name":"n","salience":0.03013068623840809},{"name":"memory","salience":0.029288439080119133},{"name":"shows","salience":0.02822275087237358},{"name":"lab","salience":0.028018293902277946},{"name":"difference","salience":0.027444051578640938},{"name":"some","salience":0.026400092989206314},{"name":"bignum *res","salience":0.024569114670157433},{"name":"bignum m","salience":0.024569114670157433},{"name":"n","salience":0.02265489473938942},{"name":"n","salience":0.02112886868417263},{"name":"regards","salience":0.01353206392377615},{"name":"n","salience":0.011326945386826992},{"name":"memory","salience":0.009714340791106224},{"name":"address","salience":0.008533911779522896},{"name":"raymond","salience":0.00800483487546444}],"question":" Hi there! Can anyone help me with void addBigNums(BigNum n, BigNum m, BigNum *res) function in Week 2 lab? Why does some of the functions shows n while some shows *n? What are the difference? I understand *n means it is a pointer to where the memory is located while n means the actual address of the memory, is this correct? When do I use *n and when do I use n? Thank you. Regards, Raymond ","answers":[" *n means that the parameter value being passed is a pointer to a BigNum structure. n means that the parameter value being passed is an actual BigNum object. You use no star if you simply want to supply a value to a function (this is analogous to regular function arguments in maths). You use a star if you want to pass in a pointer to an object in the caller, and the intention of the function is to change the thing being pointed to. Think about scanf(\"%d\",&amp;x) . The intention is to change the value of x , so we need to pass a pointer to x to the scanf function. All of this might become clearer when we see how functions are implemented in MIPS. ",[" Hi Dr. Shepherd! Allright, I will take a look again at the function. Thank you! Regards, Raymond Setiawan Soedargo "]]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums"},{"name":"lab classes"},{"name":"week 02: big numbers"},{"name":"code","salience":0.347089946269989},{"name":"autotest","salience":0.22352664172649384},{"name":"tests","salience":0.19408178329467773},{"name":"files","salience":0.14250923693180084},{"name":"commands","salience":0.0480063259601593},{"name":"someone","salience":0.04478606581687927}],"question":" I'm not sure why but my code fails the autotest, but if I do the tests manually (going through the .sh files and applying the commands there) i pass them. Can someone tell me why this is happening? ","answers":[" i know with the fifth test \"./add 20 300\" it is actually \"./add 020 300\" with a couple of spaces. so something like: \"./add 020 300\" i think you had to trim the white space? i'm not too sure why you would be failing tests 1 and 2. it could be perhaps you are printing an extra space at the end of the line? you have to make sure they are exactly the same. Use the diff command to tell you what is different. So go into your tests folder and do \"diff 1.exp 1.out\" and it will tell you what is different. if diff does not print anything to stdout, then it means they are exactly the same. ",[" Unfortunately doing diff doesn't really say much for me as shown But I did find a bug when adding 020 and 300 together So I'm going to assume the same about printing white spaces or something to do with that. Thanks! ",[" Hmmm... I'm pretty sure it isn't meant to be a binary file. Can you check something? run cat tests/1.out then run cat tests/3.out and see what happens. I'd be interested to see if it prints the contents of 3.out "],[" may i ask how do you go about the showBigNum function? in your printf line, are you using %c or %d? ",[" %c, in a for loop that ends when it reaches '\\0' I fixed the issue (it was white trailing space!) but I'm failing the 5th test so I just need to fix it up. Thanks for your help ",[" woohoo! good luck! "]]]]," Hi Stella, Have a look at the .exp files (expected output) of test 3 and 4 and how they might be different to the rest of the tests. You might see a pattern there that helps you. "," Did you check the differences between expected and observed output? And without seeing your code or having more info on the output your program is producing, nobody will be able to tell you why. ",[" I couldn't check observed output, but I got some ideas to check if I'm printing white spaces or not so I'll try that first. ",[" The file tests/2.out is not a folder. It's a file. Can you open it as a file? "]]]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums"},{"name":"lab classes"},{"name":"week 02: big numbers"},{"name":"chars","salience":0.13504339754581451},{"name":"string","salience":0.13504339754581451},{"name":"stdin","salience":0.13504339754581451},{"name":"array","salience":0.13504339754581451},{"name":"trouble","salience":0.13504339754581451},{"name":"struct","salience":0.05316679924726486},{"name":"strncpy","salience":0.04641519859433174},{"name":"examples","salience":0.04285812750458717},{"name":"strncpy","salience":0.03214877098798752},{"name":"bignum","salience":0.031735941767692566},{"name":"bytes","salience":0.02355054020881653},{"name":"assignment","salience":0.023147236555814743},{"name":"bytes","salience":0.02162504568696022},{"name":"errors","salience":0.019278135150671005},{"name":"versions","salience":0.015777334570884705},{"name":"anyone","salience":0.008551805280148983},{"name":"advice","salience":0.006528092548251152}],"question":" I am having trouble copying the chars in the string provided from stdin to the array in the BigNum struct. I have tried simple assignment, strncpy and even atoi but keep getting compile errors. Here are some high level examples of which I have tried various different versions: n-&gt;bytes[j] = atoi(s[i]); n-&gt;bytes[j] = s[i]; strncpy(n-&gt;bytes, s+j, 1); strncpy(n-&gt;bytes[i], s[j], 1); Can anyone provide any advice? ","answers":[" Are you talking about the scanBigNum function? i think with strncpy the third parameter should not be 1, if you look at the man page, the third parameter should be the size of the string, which you can get by \"strlen(s)\" Also when scanning in, you have to reverse the numbers (123 should stored as 321) it makes the addition part way easier. i basically used a for loop, which is simple when you have the length of the string, then in the loop i did: n-&gt;bytes[i] = s[*insert expression here to reverse*] i hope this helps, if not, keep asking questions. ",[" Thanks Alex, Yes, referring to scanBigNum. I was using 1 with strncpy as I was wanting to use it to copy just a single char from the string and then place that into the appropriate element in the n-&gt;bytes string, tha being, in the reverse order. However I am not sure if it can be used that way and it needs to copy the entire string. I had initially used n-&gt;bytes[j] = s[i]; format but was getting \"illegal array, pointer or other operation\" errors at runtime. So found no reason to use strncpy nor had similiar runtime errors? Thanks ",[" strncpy can be used the copy a single char, but probably won't help, because it will set the next char in the array to '\\0', which will wipe out anything you'd put there earlier. n-&gt;bytes[i] = ch; would be the way to do it, assuming that your array was set up properly, and it sounds like your isn't. ",[" Thanks John, I will investigate further. "]]]]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums"},{"name":"lab classes"},{"name":"week 02: big numbers"}],"question":" [deleted] ","answers":[" Nevermind. Found the issue. "]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums"},{"name":"lab classes"},{"name":"week 02: big numbers"}],"question":" [deleted] ","answers":[" Maybe just type in make (not necessarily make BigNum)? ",[" Thanks! "]]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums"},{"name":"lab classes"},{"name":"week 02: big numbers"},{"name":"function","salience":0.5634146928787231},{"name":"function","salience":0.1278778612613678},{"name":"failure","salience":0.1034853607416153},{"name":"following","salience":0.1034853607416153},{"name":"assertion","salience":0.02128836326301098},{"name":"intlistok","salience":0.014077155850827694},{"name":"list","salience":0.013634299859404564},{"name":"testing","salience":0.010968861170113087},{"name":"myotherlist","salience":0.007279288023710251},{"name":"order","salience":0.006456463132053614},{"name":"numbers","salience":0.006456463132053614},{"name":"program","salience":0.006456463132053614},{"name":"thanks","salience":0.006442029494792223},{"name":"line","salience":0.004073801916092634},{"name":"useintlist.","salience":0.002408590167760849},{"name":"anybody","salience":0.002194917993620038}],"question":" I keep getting the following assert failure, but my function works otherwise. I know that means it doesn't really work, but the 'IntListOK' function isn't really documented and I don't see how it's causing my function to fail. Assertion failed: (IntListOK(myOtherList)), function main, file useIntList.c, line 25. Does anybody know roughly what that assert is testing? Because my function produces a list in order of all the numbers input into the program. Thanks! ","answers":[" Is this in relation to lab 02? I don’t see this assert in the main function of add.c. I have a feeling you posted in the wrong course... did you mean to post in CS2521? ",[" oh my god, yes sorry! Wrong course. "]]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums"},{"name":"lab classes"},{"name":"week 02: big numbers"},{"name":"error message","salience":0.42002159357070923},{"name":"test","salience":0.20233683288097382},{"name":"result","salience":0.11095600575208664},{"name":"result","salience":0.07826803624629974},{"name":"laptop","salience":0.05710505694150925},{"name":"printing results","salience":0.04794221743941307},{"name":"size error","salience":0.04484743997454643},{"name":"help","salience":0.021063433960080147},{"name":"one","salience":0.01745939627289772}],"question":" Hi, I gotta an error message like this and the only test I couldn't pass is the \"tests 9\". When I printed out my result at my own laptop, the result is exactly same as the one supposed to be. Why would it getting size error but the printing results are same? Any help would be much appreciated. ","answers":[" Programs with errors behave in unpredictable ways, depending on what happens in the underlying system. This is going to be a recurring theme in this course. This is why we want you to understand what happens when the program executes. Looking at the error message, my guess is that you've overflowed a buffer and messed up the heap, which manifests as the invalid size error. It might happen to work on your laptop because it uses a different implementation of malloc() where the buffer overflow doesn't have the same effect. "]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums"},{"name":"lab classes"},{"name":"week 02: big numbers"},{"name":"issues","salience":0.2906407415866852},{"name":"realloc","salience":0.2906407415866852},{"name":"error","salience":0.06800128519535065},{"name":"c","salience":0.060996755957603455},{"name":"numbers","salience":0.05576835200190544},{"name":"size","salience":0.03893196955323219},{"name":"assertion","salience":0.038460876792669296},{"name":"tests","salience":0.026774300262331963},{"name":"dl_pagesize","salience":0.023108555004000664},{"name":"glro","salience":0.023108555004000664},{"name":"help","salience":0.02305787429213524},{"name":"apprecated","salience":0.02305787429213524},{"name":"thanks","salience":0.018726058304309845},{"name":"advance","salience":0.018726058304309845}],"question":" I think I'm having some issues with realloc(). The error I get is: add: malloc.c:2868: mremap_chunk: Assertion `((size + offset) &amp; (GLRO (dl_pagesize) - 1)) == 0' failed. It is only when I am adding 2 very large numbers. Such as tests 8 and 9. Any help would be much apprecated, Thanks in advance :) ","answers":[" Hi Brendan, I suspect the pointer you are passing to malloc may not be valid. The only pointers you can pass in to realloc are NULL or a pointer that's previously been returned from malloc(). Is it possible you passed in a pointer to a local variable, instead of a pointer that's on the heap (ie. from malloc)? ",[" Or perhaps you ran over the end of a malloc'd buffer earlier. Doing that inevitably messes up the heap so that future malloc's are likely to fail (possibly in other parts of the program away from the original error). This one of the \"joys\" of C's dynamic memory management. You could try compiling with dcc , which reasonably good at detecting and reporting such problems. "]]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums"},{"name":"lab classes"},{"name":"week 02: big numbers"},{"name":"segmentatiom fault","salience":1}],"question":" Whenever I try to make add, after I run it I get a segmentatiom fault. What does this mean and how do I fix it? ","answers":[" A segmentation fault is from an illegal memory access. It is often the result of trying to access an array element and going too far off the end, or dereferencing an invalid pointer. For example, you could get a segfault if you loop over an array but go one too far, or if you try to loop over an array where no memory has been allocated to it. "]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums"},{"name":"lab classes"},{"name":"week 02: big numbers"},{"name":"bignum","salience":0.42221254110336304},{"name":"code","salience":0.34767094254493713},{"name":"tests","salience":0.1269996613264084},{"name":"bignum","salience":0.10311687737703323}],"question":" Hi I realised just now that I've scanned in the bignum opposite from what we're supposed to, however my code passes the tests. Would I get penalised for implementing an opposite bignum? ","answers":[" No. We're more interested that you can produce a working solution ... and also that the code is readable and reasonably efficient. "]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums"},{"name":"lab classes"},{"name":"week 02: big numbers"},{"name":"challenge exercise","salience":0.19963690638542175},{"name":"c file","salience":0.13481083512306213},{"name":"file","salience":0.12535130977630615},{"name":"functions","salience":0.10964731127023697},{"name":"bignum.","salience":0.09505649656057358},{"name":"tutor","salience":0.07570630311965942},{"name":"files","salience":0.07013029605150223},{"name":"mutiplybignums","salience":0.06512101739645004},{"name":"subtractbignums","salience":0.06432994455099106},{"name":"challenge exercises","salience":0.06020957976579666}],"question":" Hi. If I have finally completed the challenge exercise, should I submit BigNum.c file with the \"subtractBigNums\" and \"mutiplyBigNums\" functions I manually added, or put them in a separate file to submit? Or show them to my tutor instead? Since I didn't see any files containing the challenge exercises.. ","answers":[" It's harmless to include them in the BigNum.c that you submit, as long as that version passes all of the check tests. If you want the bonus, you'll need to demonstrate to your tutor that your functions actually work. "]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums"},{"name":"lab classes"},{"name":"week 02: big numbers"},{"name":"bignum","salience":0.41055166721343994},{"name":"digits","salience":0.22662046551704407},{"name":"result","salience":0.17825675010681152},{"name":"subtractbignums","salience":0.09487985074520111},{"name":"character","salience":0.08969126641750336}],"question":" Because BigNum is only supposed to hold chars of digits from 0..9, for subtractBigNums() can we assume that the result will always be positive, or do we extend this to include a '-' character? ","answers":[" You should implement negatives, but it doesn't necessarily have to be with a character in the bytes array, it could be stored on the struct. "]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums"},{"name":"lab classes"},{"name":"week 02: big numbers"},{"name":"numbers","salience":0.19903682172298431},{"name":"numbers","salience":0.18832285702228546},{"name":"c","salience":0.17625002562999725},{"name":"bignum.","salience":0.1209203451871872},{"name":"length","salience":0.06918276846408844},{"name":"characters","salience":0.05340518429875374},{"name":"scanning","salience":0.047005388885736465},{"name":"reasons","salience":0.022445397451519966},{"name":"size","salience":0.021009864285588264},{"name":"nbytes","salience":0.021009864285588264},{"name":"malloc","salience":0.021009864285588264},{"name":"someone","salience":0.018701927736401558},{"name":"code extracts","salience":0.015798494219779968},{"name":"chars","salience":0.007930291816592216},{"name":"argv","salience":0.006966825574636459},{"name":"array","salience":0.006314428057521582}],"question":" Can't Scan Big Numbers: Hi, my BigNum.c works fine for numbers that are relatively small in length (~20 characters), but stops scanning after that. What are some possible reasons for it to do that? (I think) I've ensured that the size (nbytes &amp; malloc'd array of chars) of BigNum matches the argv[] exactly. Not sure if I can post code extracts, so I won't. Can someone please help me :D ","answers":[" Easiest to debug if you can see the code ... BUT don't post it here. Take it along to one of the Help Sessions "]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums"},{"name":"lab classes"},{"name":"week 02: big numbers"},{"name":"command","salience":0.9665549397468567},{"name":"bignum.c","salience":0.033445075154304504}],"question":" is this the correct give command? \"give cs1521 lab02 BigNum.c\" ","answers":[" yes it looks correct. Is it not working? ",[" it is working but i also have made changes to BigNum.h and i have added sub.c and mul.c ",[" Ok, the give command will only upload your BigNum.c file, I don't think it will let you upload those (you can try by adding the file names after BigNum.c) but I'd suggest just showing the extension work to a tutor next week in class. "]]]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums"},{"name":"lab classes"},{"name":"week 02: big numbers"},{"name":"tests","salience":0.2575574219226837},{"name":"program","salience":0.22797130048274994},{"name":"issue","salience":0.22533684968948364},{"name":"input","salience":0.16034995019435883},{"name":"tests","salience":0.12878447771072388}],"question":" Hello, I've been trying to figuring the issue with these 3 tests my program can't pass, how do i find out what input is received during these tests? ","answers":[" Look in the tests/ directory. "]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums"},{"name":"lab classes"},{"name":"week 02: big numbers"},{"name":"warm-up question","salience":0.557054877281189},{"name":"hexadecimal","salience":0.44294512271881104}],"question":" For the warm-up question, can I use %04x to print the hexadecimal? ","answers":[" does the \"04\" pad it with zeroes such that the length of the string is always 4? i changed all my %xs to %04x and i saw no change. ",[" %&lt;var&gt;n&lt;/var&gt;d pads right to the width of &lt;var&gt;n&lt;/var&gt;, with spaces. %0&lt;var&gt;n&lt;/var&gt;d pads right to the width of &lt;var&gt;n&lt;/var&gt;, with zeroes. %-&lt;var&gt;n&lt;/var&gt;d pads left to the width of &lt;var&gt;n&lt;/var&gt;, with spaces. "]," I am not sure about this. I think it should be output as 0x000000 form. So the prefix for hexadecimal should be 0x. ",[" i'm also not sure about this, but i think it is fine without the prefix. i know that %p can give you the prefix while %x will just print it out in hex. i think %p is used more for printing memory locations. either way it should be too hard to add the prefix if needed. ",[" %p is the format code for an address, not for a general hexadecimal number. You should use %x instead. "],[" Yep. I agree with you. %p is print out the memory address. I think 0x %x should be fine. "]]]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums"},{"name":"lab classes"},{"name":"week 02: big numbers"},{"name":"number","salience":0.309689998626709},{"name":"tests","salience":0.29420262575149536},{"name":"picture","salience":0.09698913991451263},{"name":"output","salience":0.07737351208925247},{"name":"problem","salience":0.07645509392023087},{"name":"direction","salience":0.05398267135024071},{"name":"thanks","salience":0.03801247105002403},{"name":"number","salience":0.027222316712141037},{"name":"anyone","salience":0.02607215940952301}],"question":" I've passed all the tests except the 9th one and was wondering what was causing the problem, attached is a picture of my output and it seems like the first number is being overlapped by the second number, if anyone could point me in the right direction it would be great, thanks! ./add 123123123123123123123123123123123123123 9879879879879879879987987879879879 ","answers":[" With only that amount of info, it sounds like one of your arrays isn't big enough and you've overflowed into the other array. Check whether your check for array being full is ok, and then check that your code to increase array size is ok. Best to ask your tutor or at a Help Session. "]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums"},{"name":"lab classes"},{"name":"week 02: big numbers"},{"name":"challenge","salience":0.529569685459137},{"name":"sign","salience":0.17902438342571259},{"name":"number","salience":0.17295099794864655},{"name":"output","salience":0.05285387858748436},{"name":"numbers","salience":0.04223978519439697},{"name":"string","salience":0.02336125634610653}],"question":" About lab02 challenge Exercises, Do we need to consider negative number? like 3-5=-2, Do we need to add negative sign to the string and output it, or we can ignore negative numbers? ","answers":[" yes you should consider negative numbers. As part of the challenge, you need to come up with a more compact structure, so you can change the struct however you like to take into account negative numbers. Just make sure it’s backwards compatible with the original test cases, add function, etc. "," idk i guess you can add it in if you want. i just added an int is_negative in the BigNum struct, then in the sub function, if m &gt; n, then i would do a sub(m,n,res) and set res-&gt;is_negative to 1. "]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums"},{"name":"lab classes"},{"name":"week 02: big numbers"},{"name":"program","salience":0.24094444513320923},{"name":"numbers","salience":0.0829375758767128},{"name":"exp","salience":0.07811374962329865},{"name":"tests","salience":0.069483682513237},{"name":"test5","salience":0.06458142399787903},{"name":"test","salience":0.043762627989053726},{"name":"files","salience":0.04340871796011925},{"name":"exp","salience":0.03815267235040665},{"name":"all","salience":0.03806757554411888},{"name":"test file","salience":0.03712250292301178},{"name":"information","salience":0.03509626165032387},{"name":"output","salience":0.029153499752283096},{"name":"answer","salience":0.02825855277478695},{"name":"information","salience":0.024218013510107994},{"name":"output","salience":0.024218013510107994},{"name":"program","salience":0.023974353447556496},{"name":"diff","salience":0.02127815969288349},{"name":"test files","salience":0.021137164905667305},{"name":"something","salience":0.017872599884867668},{"name":"files","salience":0.014640125446021557},{"name":"files","salience":0.012946687638759613},{"name":"other","salience":0.010631591081619263}],"question":" Hi, I am doing lab02 now which is about calculating big numbers. And I almost finished, but I tried to test it. Unfortunately it passed all tests except test5. And I checked the test file. It includes .exp and .out files. And I thought that's all for testing my program. But I opened test 5.exp and use the information inside to test my program directly. And the output matches the answer in 5.exp. But when I compared 5.out with other .out files, I found that the other .out files are all vacant but 5.out includes the information exactly same with the output I use diff after I test my program. Hence, Is there any program with the test files? Or is there something I understand incorrectly? ","answers":[" The 5.exp file is the expected output from running test 5 (in the 5.sh file) The 5.out file is the one that your program produced when you ran the check command. I'm not sure whether that answers your question ... ",[" Oh, actually when I tried to test ./add 020 \" 300 \" I found the weakness of my function. Thanks very much. "],[" Is the test .sh file correct? ./add 020 \" 300 \" as compared to ./add 020 300 -- Added some extra code into my `add.c`, this is what I get ",[" The 5.sh file is correct. It's checking for how you handle spaces around a number The example should have only three argv values: argv[0] = \"./add\", argv[1] = \"020\", argv[2] = \" 300 \" ",[" Actually, on second thoughts, it seems that the issue was the way that I was running the tests "]]]]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums"},{"name":"lab classes"},{"name":"week 02: big numbers"},{"name":"warm up exercise","salience":0.44566524028778076},{"name":"pow","salience":0.29233548045158386},{"name":"math library","salience":0.1600903570652008},{"name":"function","salience":0.10190891474485397}],"question":" With the warm up exercise, am i allowed to use the pow() function from the math library? ","answers":[" The warm-up is working with integer values. pow() works with doubles. I'm not sure how it helps. ",[" I know that with the unsigned data types i can underflow them and that will give the biggest value. But I'm still a little lost with the other data types. two methods come to my mind. 1. keep incrementing by 1 until you detect an overflow and return the value. (probably takes a long time). 2. Use the pow() where the base is 2 and the power is the number of bits. i type casted pow() to the appropriate data type. e.g. (int) pow(...) One weird thing that i have notice is that if i incorrectly put the power number higher that it should be, the int data type does not overflow? ' int x = (int) pow(2, 4*10)' does not overflow but when i increment it, it will overflow. ",[" Try using &lt;&lt; for powers of 2. ",[" Thanks! "]]]]}]}